Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So today we are going to continue the discussion about the storage devices.
今天我们将继续讨论存储设备的话题。
In particular, we are going to talk about ss ds or solid state devices.
具体而言，我们将讨论固态设备，也就是固态硬盘（SSD）。
We are going to start the discussion on queuing theory.
我们将开始讨论排队理论。
Last time, we talked about this drives or the spinning disks.
上次我们讨论了这些驱动器或旋转硬盘。
And these are the main technology used to store data
以下是用于存储数据的主要技术：
1. 硬盘驱动器（HDD）：硬盘驱动器是一种机械式存储设备，使用旋转磁盘和磁头来读取和写入数据。它具有较大的存储容量和较低的成本，适用于长期存储和大容量数据存储。
2. 固态驱动器（SSD）：固态驱动器使用闪存存储技术，没有机械部件，因此读写速度更快，能耗更低。它适用于需要快速访问和高性能的应用，如操作系统和数据库。
3. 光盘：光盘使用激光技术读取和写入数据。常见的光盘类型包括CD（音频和数据）、DVD（数字视频和数据）和蓝光光盘（高清视频和数据）。光盘适用于长期存储和传输数据，但读写速度较慢。
4. 闪存驱动器：闪存驱动器是一种便携式存储设备，使用闪存存储技术。它具有较小的体积、较高的读写速度和较低的能耗，适用于个人文件存储和数据传输。
5. 云存储：云存储是将数据存储在远程服务器上的技术。用户可以通过互联网访问和管理存储在云中的数据。云存储具有高可靠性、可扩展性和灵活性，适用于数据备份、共享和远程访问。
这些技术在不同的应用场景中都有各自的优势和适用性。根据需求和预算，选择适合的存储技术非常重要。
for the first few decades of
在最初的几十年中
personal computers and computers in general.
个人电脑和一般的计算机。
And with starting with kind of two decades ago,
从大约二十年前开始，
a little bit more than that.
比那稍微多一点点。
It's we started to see the emergence of us another technology to start data
我们开始看到另一种技术的出现，用于开始数据处理。
persistently.
持久地。
That was memory based.
那是基于内存的。
And the first efforts was in 1995 is the emergencies of you have d ram.
1995年是你们开始努力的第一次，那时候出现了D RAM的紧急情况。
But how you make it persistent,
但是你如何使其持久化？
you have a battery.
你有一个电池。
You have been empowered by a battery.
你已经被电池赋予了能量。
As long as a battery lasts,
只要电池能持续使用，
you are going to store the data persistently in that memory.
你将会将数据持久地存储在那块内存中。
Even when the computer or it's unplugged.
即使计算机或者它被拔掉电源。
After that,
之后，
things change with this new technology and multiple cells.
随着这种新技术和多个单元的出现，事物发生了变化。
So basically, this allows you to store is like a memory,
基本上，这允许你像存储器一样存储数据。
but it allows you to start data is to start information even when it's not power.
但它允许你在没有电源的情况下启动数据和信息。
Okay?
好的？
So that was kind of the key technology innovation.
所以这就是关键的技术创新。
As a high level.
作为一个高级别。
There are many tell us,
有很多事情告诉我们，
we don't have a lot of time to go into it, tell us.
我们没有太多时间来详细讨论，告诉我们吧。
But the big sink was about
但是最大的问题是关于洗手池
having this commercially available the technology to store data
将这项技术商业化，用于存储数据。
without in this kind of new kind of memories,
在这种新型记忆体中没有
without needing to power them on.
无需将其开机。
And this ss ds,
这是什么东西？
these are going to,
这些即将要做的事情。
they have they story information and gravity of a memory block and a memory
它们具有存储块和内存的故事信息和重力。
block.
阻塞。
It's consist of four kilobytes page of between 4and64 kilobytes pages.
它由4KB大小的页面组成，每个页面的大小介于4KB到64KB之间。
Remember that 4 kilobytes pages is basically more or less like a sector
请记住，4千字节的页面基本上可以看作是一个扇区。
on a disk describe.
在磁盘上描述。
It's also may can be the size of the page for of a virtual memory
这也可能是虚拟内存的页面大小。
implementation.
实现。
You have virtual page, the pages of visual memory, the pages,
你有虚拟页面，视觉内存的页面，页面。
individual memory,
个体内存
typically four kilobytes.
通常为四千字节。
The same, the size is a sector size.
相同，大小是一个扇区大小。
And then when you translate those to this as these,
然后当你将那些翻译成这些时，
you are going for this formula by stage are part of a memory block.
你正在按阶段将这个公式分解成内存块的一部分。
And a memory block consist of four between four and cd four.
一个内存块由四个字节到十六个字节之间的数据组成。
Vegas.
维加斯。
This is an important detail.
这是一个重要的细节。
There are no moving parts.
没有任何可动部件。
We just like memory.
我们就像内存一样。
This has a certain advantages,
这有一定的优势，
big advantages.
巨大的优势。
First of all, eliminate the sick and the rotational latency.
首先，消除病态和旋转延迟。
Remember, from last time,
记得，上次的内容是，
there's a sick and rotational latency,
存在疾病和旋转延迟。
where the biggest culprits of a long latency to access data on the disk
造成磁盘数据访问延迟最大的罪魁祸首在哪里？
that is randomly.
这是随机的。
But that's why we have a huge difference between the throughput of a disk
这就是为什么磁盘吞吐量之间存在巨大差异的原因。
when you access a data sequentially.
当你按顺序访问数据时。
Because in that particular case,
因为在那种特定情况下，
you do not need to pay for the sick and rotation delays,
你不需要为病假和轮换延迟支付费用。
versus when you access the data randomly,
相比于随机访问数据时，
when you need to pay for a boss of this delays,
当你需要为这些延迟付出代价时，
six elevation,
六个高度，
they also have requires even lower, very,
它们还有更低的要求，非常低。
very low power and anything,
非常低功耗和任何东西。
and they are liked wet.
它们喜欢潮湿的环境。
This is not just memory.
这不仅仅是内存。
It's not like a disk matter, always.
并不总是像磁盘问题那样。
Bladder as soon as spinning and heads and things like that on the downside,
当膀胱开始旋转并出现头部等问题时，情况就不太好了。
it does have limited right cycles.
它确实有有限的权利循环。
This means that limited the right cycle is when you modify a sadly,
这意味着有限的循环权是指当你修改一个遗憾时，
when you modify a bit,
当你修改一个位时，
you cannot,
你不能这样做。
if you modify it too many times,
如果你修改它太多次，
if you write the same, but a bit,
如果你写得一样，只是稍微改动一下，
too many times, then it works out.
尝试了很多次，最终成功了。
You can no longer ride that bit reliably.
你不能再可靠地使用那个位(bit)了。
And so that's one the challenge you need to deal with.
这就是你需要应对的挑战之一。
And obviously,
显然，
things are introduced their own rapid advantage,
事物引入了自己的快速优势，
and the capacity have increased.
容量也增加了。
And today,
今天，
to give you a sense,
给你一个概念，
obviously,
显然，
today is that I am not sure any of your devices you are working
今天是我不确定你正在使用的任何设备的一天。
with still has a disk unless you are working,
只有在你工作时，计算机才会保持硬盘运转。
you have a big workstation home or you are using.
你在家里有一台大型工作站或者你正在使用一台。
But certainly your laptops,
但是当然你们的笔记本电脑，
obviously, the phones,
显然，手机，
ipo ipad,
IPO指的是首次公开募股（Initial Public Offering），是指公司首次向公众发行股票并在证券交易所上市交易的过程。
iPad是由苹果公司开发和销售的一款平板电脑。
or they no longer have these drives as to start data persistently.
或者他们不再拥有这些驱动器来持久保存数据。
They only have ss ds.
他们只有SS和DS。
Here it's again how as the architecture look like,
这是架构的外观如何看起来的描述。
this lands is where on the right hand side is a memory,
这块土地上的右手边是一片内存区域。
the banks of memory.
内存的银行。
And each of these could present a block.
每个都可以表示为一个块。
And then you have a flash memory controller,
然后你有一个闪存控制器，
which basically decides where to write and or to read the data from,
这基本上决定了从哪里写入或读取数据。
you have a buffer manager and a softer queue.
你有一个缓冲区管理器和一个软件队列。
This is about when this is where you buffer the reads and writes requests.
这是关于在何时何地缓冲读写请求的问题。
Say we have many reads or write requests at the same time,
假设我们同时有许多读取或写入请求，
and you cannot serve at the same time.
你不能同时服务两个人。
You have to buffer them and it sell them1×1.
你需要将它们缓冲并逐个出售。
It's also ad ram here.
这里也是内存。
So when you cache some of the information, right?
所以当你缓存一些信息时，对吗？
When you read, if I read only a few bites,
当你阅读时，如果我只读了几个字节，
the granularity, if you remember,
如果你还记得的话，粒度
to read and write from this ssd it is one of this memory blocks,
要从这个SSD中读取和写入数据，需要选择其中一个内存块。
which can be between 16and256kilobytes.
可以在16到256千字节之间。
You have to read the diagram of granularity.
你需要阅读粒度图表。
And once you are reading it,
当你阅读它的时候，
you are going to cash it.
你打算兑现它。
If you are going to or write,
如果你要去或写作，
if you are going to read again,
如果你打算再次阅读，
the next few bytes,
接下来的几个字节，
then it's already in the alarm.
那么它已经处于警报状态了。
You don't need to go and fetch it, fetch it again.
你不需要去取它，再去取一次。
Now, and this is the satire.
现在，这就是讽刺之处。
It's a bus technology,
这是一种总线技术，
and or can be bc bs which is connected to the through a bridge to the pci bus,
and or 可以是 bc 或 bs，它们通过桥接到 PCI 总线。
like we discussed last time.
就像我们上次讨论的那样。
And then it's connected to the processor and is a memory.
然后它与处理器连接并作为内存使用。
Here are some numbers for you to read a four kilobyte page.
这里有一些数字，用于读取一个四千字节的页面。
It takes around, say,
大约需要，比如说，
between 10and25 micro seconds.
在10到25微秒之间。
Again, there is no segal rotational latency.
再次强调，不存在Segal旋转延迟。
Now, the transfer time for that four kilobytes page,
现在，这个四千字节页面的传输时间是多少？
for the satire interface,
对于Satire接口，
you have between three hundred six hundred megabytes per second.
你的速度在每秒三百到六百兆字节之间。
Actually,
实际上，
the best interface is today you have two gigabytes or mega two gigabytes
最好的接口是今天你有两个千兆字节或两个兆字节。
per second.
每秒。
So a few times larger than this.
比这个大几倍。
But even for us for, say,
但即使对于我们来说，比如说，
400 megabytes per second to take a number,
每秒400兆字节的速度进行计算。
then the transfer time.
然后是传输时间。
So the time to read 4 kilo by spade is send micro seconds.
所以读取4千字节的数据需要发送的时间是以微秒计算的。
And the latency, if you remember,
而且如果你还记得的话，延迟问题也是一个重要因素。
what is atlanta and latency is a queuing time.
亚特兰大是一个城市，延迟是指排队时间。
So the time it the request has to wake in the cure for other requests
所以请求需要在队列中等待的时间是为了处理其他请求。
to be satisfied plus a controller time,
满足加上控制器时间，
whatever the controller needs to do and to make the decision.
控制器需要做的事情以及做出决策。
It's a fixed time and the transfer time.
这是一个固定的时间和传输时间。
Right?
对吗？
Because this is a memory is basically around.
因为这是一个基本上围绕着内存的问题。
You can randomly address.
你可以随机访问。
There is not such a big difference between sequential and random reads.
顺序读取和随机读取之间并没有太大的区别。
Now, this was about the read.
现在，这是关于读取的内容。
Now the writing is much more complex.
现在的写作更加复杂了。
And you can only write empty pages a in a block.
而且你只能在一个块中写入空白页。
Right?
对吗？
There is a there are three states of these pages.
这些页面有三种状态。
It's written those two stages,
这两个阶段被描述为：
whether it's redone and or it, whether it's erased,
无论是重新做还是擦除，
and you can or empty.
你可以选择留空或者清空。
And you can only write empty pages.
而且你只能写空白页。
So if a page is,
那么如果一个页面是，
you want to overwrite the page,
你想要覆盖该页面。
then before doing that,
在这之前，
you need to erase a page.
你需要擦除一页。
Now the bait becomes empty,
现在诱饵变空了，
and then you're overwrite it.
然后你会覆盖它。
Now,
现在，
the problem with that is that these operations are far more expensive,
问题在于这些操作的成本要高得多，
far more expensive.
远远更昂贵。
Remember, it's like the reader say 25microsecond.
记住，这就像读者说的是25微秒。
The writing data on an empty page is 200microsecond.
在空白页面上写入数据需要200微秒。
Right now, if you want to erase a page,
现在，如果你想要擦除一页，
if you need to erase a page,
如果你需要擦除一页，
if you don't have an empty page,
如果你没有空白页，
they raise, they're raising.
他们提高了，他们正在提高。
The page takes1.5millisecond.
该页面需要1.5毫秒。
Okay?
好的？
The rule of thumb you can think about the right is 10
你可以将这个经验法则记住，即向右转动10次。
times more expensive than the reeds.
比芦苇贵多少倍。
And the rangers are 10 times more expensive than the rights, right?
是的，游侠比权利贵十倍，对吗？
So25 than 200microsecond,
小于200微秒
it's around 8 times larger than 25microsecond,
它大约比25微秒大8倍。
which is a time to takes to read a page.
这是读取一页所需的时间。
Then1.5millisecond is what?
1.5毫秒是多少？
7.5times larger than 200 microsecond is a time to read to do, right?
7.5倍于200微秒的时间是读取所需的时间，对吗？
An empty page.
一个空白页面。
So therefore, you need to be very careful about that, right?
所以，你需要非常小心对待这个问题，对吗？
This is a thing that took constraints.
这是一个有限制条件的事情。
You have to operate with the two constraints, which are different,
你需要处理两个不同的约束条件。
make this ssd is different than the d ram,
使这个固态硬盘与内存条不同。
the traditional memory.
传统内存。
It's one.
是的，已经完成了。
It's about, you can only write empty pages.
这是关于只能写空白页的问题。
And breed and rights are asymmetric,
繁殖和权利是不对称的。
are not taking the same amount of time,
不需要花费相同的时间，
a range of the cuban one longer.
一个范围的古巴人更长。
This is one then.
这是一个例子。
And the other one is that you can only do a limited amount.
另一个问题是你只能做有限的数量。
A number of rights,
一些权利，
typically is like 10,000 rights or something like that.
通常是大约10,000个权限或类似的数量。
So you need to be careful.
所以你需要小心。
Now, in order to avoid the cost of eurasia,
现在，为了避免欧亚大陆的成本，
when you need to write,
当你需要写作时，
do you raise first before writing what the controller is doing?
在编写控制器的功能之前，您是否首先提出问题？
It maintains a pool of empty blocks.
它维护了一个空块的池子。
So you bring the use pages,
所以你带来了使用页面，
put them in a put together in a blog.
将它们整理在一个博客中。
And then you have these pulls of empty blocks.
然后你会有一些空块的拉取。
And then you can write them,
然后你可以将它们写下来，
and then you can pay only 200 microsecond per page instead of1.71millisecond.
然后你只需要支付每页200微秒，而不是1.71毫秒。
Ss ds provide the same interface as hardly strives to the os the same api
Ss ds 提供与操作系统相同的接口，并努力提供相同的 API。
which is great,
这很棒，
because you can just swap and describe with an ssd and your computer will work,
因为你只需要用固态硬盘进行交换和描述，你的计算机就能正常工作。
but will be much faster.
但速度会更快。
Right?
对吗？
Like I said, when you override the data,
就像我说的，当你覆盖数据时，
when you the karanoid of writing,
当你变得过于焦虑写作时，
a it's a block,
这是一个块。
and the block can be 16 times larger than a page.
每个块的大小可以是页面的16倍。
Sorry, 67,
抱歉，67。
64times larger than a page.
比一个页面大64倍。
So you have a pages four kilobytes,
所以你有一个页面大小为四千字节，
and you have 64 pages in a block.
每个块有64页。
Then 64 by time times 4is256kilobytes.
64乘以时间乘以4等于256千字节。
This is what?
这是什么？
The25060~50,
这是一个不完整的句子，无法确定具体含义。请提供更多上下文或完整的句子。
256 kilobytes is coming from.
256 kilobytes是从哪里来的。
So I will only discuss about it.
所以我只会讨论它。
Why not erase and rewrite new version of the entire 256blocks,
为什么不擦除并重写整个256个块的新版本呢？
because eurasia is extremely slow.
因为欧亚大陆的网速非常慢。
And then each block has a finite lifetime,
然后每个块都有有限的生命周期，
like I mentioned to you,
就像我之前跟你提到的一样，
you cannot, you erase and rewrite all the time.
你不能这样做，你一直在擦除和重写。
You can only do that for, say, ten,
你只能这样做，比如说十个。
a few tens of the 10,000 of times.
几十万次中的几十次。
Therefore, if you have heavily used blocks,
因此，如果你使用的块非常频繁，
you do a lot of rights.
你做了很多正确的事情。
They are going to wear out quickly.
它们会很快磨损。
Now you have this problem, right?
现在你遇到这个问题了，对吗？
It's like,
就像是，
if you have,
如果你有的话，
how do you are going to solve it?
你打算如何解决这个问题？
Right?
对吗？
And against the problem is that I I can do iii am allowed to do
而且问题是，我可以做的事情我都可以做。
only a limited number of rights.
只有有限的权利。
Now I have some heavy blocks.
现在我有一些重的方块。
So what i'm going to do about it,
那么我该怎么办呢？
do you have any suggestions here?
你有什么建议吗？
Remap?
重新映射？
That's exactly.
没错。
So that's very good.
那太好了。
So basically, when you are going to the right,
基本上，当你向右走时，
you are not going to write in the same place.
你不会在同一个地方写。
You are going to write to another page,
你将要写入另一页。
which was not so used in the past.
在过去并不常用的。
And then you are going to remap the page to the new block.
然后你将重新映射页面到新的块中。
You used to write the new information.
你过去常常写新的信息。
This is a layer of indirection.
这是一层间接性。
It is called flash translation layer or fdl in sst I see your map,
在SST中，它被称为闪存转换层或FDL。我看到了你的地图。
the virtual block numbers,
虚拟块号
which is uses.
这是使用的哪个？
These are the blocks actually said the patient numbers,
这些是实际上所说的病人编号的块。
the physical patient numbers,
物理患者人数
which flash memory contributes.
哪种闪存起到了贡献。
That's the way it's working.
就是这样运作的。
Right?
对吗？
From the is perspective,
从操作系统的角度来看，
you still have the same page as the same page numbers and everything.
你仍然拥有相同的页面，包括相同的页码和所有内容。
But now on the physical pages,
但是现在在物理页面上，
you have a map.
你有一张地图。
And the page number as seen by the cpo is going to map to a physical page number.
而操作系统中的页号将会映射到物理页号。
And the mapping is this,
而映射关系如下：
it's handled by the car.
由汽车处理。
It's managed by the controller.
它由控制器管理。
So the controller can remap and basically say page number one is go to fit
所以控制器可以重新映射，基本上可以说页码一是指向适配的位置。
to physical page number ten.
到物理页号为十的页面。
Next is going to go to physical page number15.
接下来要访问物理页号为15。
That's how i'm going to load balance the rights for the same page as seen
这是我将要实现的同一页面的负载均衡策略。
by the cpu
通过CPU
this is pretty much,
这基本上是这样的，
it's, again, copy on the right.
这是右边的复制品。
This is or should be obvious, right?
这是显而易见的，对吗？
Again, I do not want to copy to rewrite the same page.
再次强调，我不想复制重写同一页的内容。
Even if I want to modify a page,
即使我想修改一个页面，
I don't rewrite it because I need to erase it first.
我不会重写它，因为我需要先擦除它。
If I need to erase it, first is expensive.
如果我需要擦除它，首先是昂贵的。
So what i'm doing,
所以我在做什么，
i'm going to just create a new version of the page and then i'm going to remap
我将创建一个新版本的页面，然后重新映射。
Isn't the lifetime of ten ka ratio rights quite small?
十卡比例权益的生命周期不是很短吗？
Consider that we can use a laptop for for multiple years.
考虑到我们可以使用一台笔记本电脑多年。
It's not really I because if you really do load balancing,
这并不完全是我，因为如果你真的进行负载均衡，
really loud balancing,
非常大声的平衡，
this means that you need to write or update.
这意味着你需要编写或更新。
You can read and wrap and update like say you have one one terabyte of disk.
你可以读取、包装和更新，就像你拥有一台一TB的硬盘一样。
Right?
对吗？
So one terabyte of disk then you can write,
所以一台拥有一TB硬盘的计算机，你可以进行写入操作。
they are equivalent of 10,000 multiply with one terabyte,
它们相当于10,000乘以一太字节。
so 10 better bytes.
所以10个更好的字节。
Right?
对吗？
I think it's so mad.
我觉得这太疯狂了。
This is right.
没问题。
I can write and better bytes,
我可以写入和读取字节。
and it's hard to write and better bytes.
而且很难编写更好的字节。
But it's, again, this works.
但是，再次强调，这是有效的。
If you are going to be able to load balance, right?
如果你要实现负载均衡，对吗？
And these rights.
以及这些权利。
Right?
对吗？
This is what the controller is doing.
这是控制器正在做的事情。
The flash translation layer also ensure that there is no need
闪存转换层还确保不需要
to erase and rewrite the entire 256 blocks when making small modification
在进行小的修改时，需要擦除并重写所有256个块。
or changes.
或更改。
Ssd controller can assign mapping to spread or notice or to talk about you
SSD控制器可以分配映射以扩展、通知或讨论你。
want basically to load balance the rights.
基本上想要负载均衡权利。
This is called world level ink.
这被称为世界级墨水。
And you are doing that by the mapping and doing copy and write creating
你可以通过映射和复制写来实现这个功能。
new versions of the page,
页面的新版本
or hopefully using a page of physical page,
或者希望使用一个物理页面，
which was not written many times.
这个没有被写过很多次。
If your old version of the pages,
如果你的页面是旧版本的话，
which are you delete a file, what happened?
当你删除一个文件时，会发生什么？
Then they are very garbage collected in the background.
然后它们会在后台进行垃圾回收。
And in the background, you are going to raise them, so to make it,
在后台，你将抬高它们，以使其达到目标。
prepare them to be written again.
准备将它们重新写入。
They are ready to be written again.
它们已经准备好可以重新写入了。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
This again, was something some of the most.
这又是一些最重要的事情之一。
Now, how's it?
现在，怎么样了？
Is a compare like hardest drives with ss ds.
将硬盘与固态硬盘进行比较是一项艰巨的任务。
We'll have that in the next slide,
我们将在下一张幻灯片中呈现。
but about ss ds themselves,
但是关于ss和ds本身，
these are you can buy,
这些是你可以购买的。
these are pre are sold some of the data,
这些是预先出售的一些数据。
but you can buy 16 terabytes.
但是你可以购买16TB的存储空间。
You remember that we have 16 terabytes.
你记得我们有16TB的存储空间。
The disk we considered last time was this kind of the hard disk driver
我们上次讨论的磁盘是这种类型的硬盘驱动器。
was having the same size,
具有相同大小
16 terabytes, the same capacity.
16 terabytes，容量相同。
But that was,
但那是，
if I remember correctly,
如果我记得正确的话，
you can check that was around $500,
你可以查一下大约是500美元。
$550,
550美元。
or something like that.
或者类似的东西。
This is $55,000.
这是55,000美元。
Okay?
好的？
So it's 10 times more expensive for the same capacity.
所以同样的容量要贵10倍。
However, if you look at,
然而，如果你仔细观察，
if you look at the reads and writes the number of sequential reads and writes,
如果你观察读取和写入的数量，包括连续读取和写入的次数，
it's800 or 900.
是800还是900。
In that case, was,
在这种情况下，是的，
if I remember sequential rights,
如果我记得没错的话，"sequential rights" 是指"顺序访问权限"。
it was 260 megabytes per second.
每秒速度为260兆字节。
So this is up to almost 4 times faster.
所以这个速度快了近4倍。
And random breeds.
以及随机品种。
And rice is, there is no comparison.
米饭是无与伦比的。
You can have 100,000 breeds per second.
你每秒可以拥有10万个品种。
While a read, in the case of a disk, if you remember,
在磁盘的情况下，如果你还记得的话，读取操作
can take a few million seconds.
可能需要几百万秒的时间。
So if you takes even, you're a few million seconds.
如果你选择偶数，你需要几百万秒。
And in a second, in the in a second,
一秒钟后，再过一秒钟，
you can read a few hundreds,
你可以读几百个。
do a few hundreds retail rights in order of lying to bed.
按照躺在床上的顺序做几百个零售权益。
And if you really want to go to the top ones,
如果你真的想进入顶级公司，
we have 100 terabytes.
我们有100TB的存储空间。
So this is the 100 terabytes.
所以这就是100TB的容量。
You have 500 megabytes sequentially and rights.
您有500兆字节的连续和可写权限。
The same kind of I ops,
相同类型的I操作，
100 kilobytes,
100千字节
or I ops means are input output or input
"or I ops" 可以理解为 "或者 I 操作"，其中 I 操作可以是输入操作或输出操作。
of open operation or input operation per second
每秒的打开操作或输入操作次数
unlimited rice for 5 years.
五年无限量的大米。
So you get this guarantees.
所以你得到了这些保证。
But it costs four thousand,
但是它要花费四千美元。
$40,000.
40,000美元。
But my far more expensive, right?
但是我的价格更高，对吗？
Is like 1/4 of dollar per gigabyte.
是每千兆字节约为1/4美元。
Why would random versus sequential have different performance?
为什么随机访问和顺序访问会有不同的性能表现？
This is these.
这是这些。
As if you read at the level of pages, there is no difference.
如果你以页面为单位阅读，就没有什么区别了。
And you can do probably you can do the mask here or is very little difference.
在这里，你可能可以进行掩码操作，或者差异非常小。
But still, if you read at the level of page,
但是，如果你按页阅读的话，
because you transfer from the ss ds at the level of page or block that,
因为你在页面或块级别上从SS DS进行转移，所以这样做。
I think blog on a granality,
我认为博客的粒度很重要。
if you read only 1 byte or from that page,
如果你只读取1个字节或从该页面读取数据，
you are still going to lose in terms of performance for throughput.
就吞吐量而言，你仍然会在性能上失去。
The difference between a random,
随机的区别在于，
the different reason rises.
原因的不同产生。
The reason is different here is because remember that the rights are slower,
这里的原因不同是因为要记住权利较慢。
10 times slower, almost.
几乎慢了10倍。
Here is a comparison between hardest drives.
这是一份硬盘比较。
And I says this and this is a nice,
我说这个是很好的。
interesting plot,
有趣的情节，
because why wouldn't use as it is?
为什么不直接使用它呢？
They have all they are faster.
它们都更快。
They can have bigger capacity,
它们可以具有更大的容量。
they consume less power,
它们消耗更少的电力，
so they are more reliable.
所以它们更可靠。
So why in the world you wouldn't use that?
那么为什么你不会使用它呢？
The answer is simply is cost.
答案很简单，就是成本。
Right?
对吗？
However, and here,
然而，在这里，
what you see or is a blue line,
你所看到的是一条蓝色的线。
is a flash cost.
是一个闪存成本。
It is and for the same capacity city for the terabyte is a flash cost or a terabyte.
对于相同容量的存储设备，闪存的成本和硬盘的成本是相同的，都是按照每个 terabyte 计算的。
And here is orange is hardest drive cost.
这是橙色是最难的驱动器成本。
So the hard drive cost much cheaper than ss ds.
所以硬盘的价格比固态硬盘便宜得多。
With green, the green is the most important curve.
绿色是最重要的曲线。
Is basically what is a ratio between the cost to store one terabyte
基本上，成本与存储一TB数据的比率是什么意思？
on an ssd versus the
在SSD上与在
cost to store a terabyte on hardest drive.
存储一太字节数据在硬盘上的成本是多少？
So it was 37 times in 2013.
所以在2013年它发生了37次。
Today, it's around 56 times,
今天大约是56次。
so it's much smaller.
所以它要小得多。
And many people predict that sometime in the future,
许多人预测在将来的某个时候，
these predictions are almost always wrong.
这些预测几乎总是错误的。
But somewhere in the near future,
但在不久的将来的某个地方，
the ssd will match the cost of harvey stripes.
SSD的价格将与哈维条纹的成本相匹配。
And at that point,
在那个时候，
there is very little reasons to use harvey stripes at all.
实际上几乎没有什么理由使用哈维条纹。
Okay?
好的？
In summary,
总结一下，
this,
这个，
they have low latency, high throughput,
它们具有低延迟、高吞吐量，
no moving parts of more reliable,
没有移动部件更可靠。
lower power consumption,
低功耗
and read much faster it,
并且阅读速度更快。
read their memory speeds.
读取它们的内存速度。
You get it even faster.
你甚至更快地理解了。
If you have a wider bus,
如果你有一个更宽的总线，
by the way,
顺便说一下，
that was one of the main limitations of how fast you can read and write.
这是阅读和写作速度的主要限制之一。
The cons before02 is expensive between 3 and 20 x more expensive.
before02的缺点是价格昂贵，比3到20倍更贵。
In a few years back,
几年前，
like certainly 10 years back.
就像确实是10年前一样。
The ssd is sort of much smaller than harvey stripes.
SSD（固态硬盘）的尺寸要比哈维条纹硬盘小得多。
That's why here it's smaller storage.
这就是为什么这里的存储空间较小。
The people by exam,
考试的人们
they are combining the hardest drive with ss ds using ssd as a cash to get
他们正在将最大容量的硬盘与固态硬盘结合使用，将固态硬盘作为缓存来提高性能。
the performance of ss ds and to get the capacity of hrd stripes.
SSD和HDD的性能以及获取硬盘条带的容量。
But now there's no longer needed, right?
但现在不再需要了，对吗？
Because as you've seen from the data, now,
因为正如你从数据中看到的，现在，
the hardest ss ds can have higher capacity than hard disrupts.
最困难的固态硬盘可以比传统硬盘具有更高的容量。
Quite amazing.
非常令人惊叹。
Right?
对吗？
This says tells you this technology,
这句话告诉你这项技术，
if you are to build a company based on that,
如果你要基于这个构建一家公司，
they totally do not have been a good,
他们完全没有做得好。
great idea because the trends are not in your favor, right?
很好的想法，因为趋势对你不利，对吗？
By because they're your product to use ss ds to speed up,
因为它们是你要使用的产品，可以加快速度。
the hardest drives would have become obsolete.
最困难的硬盘将会变得过时。
There's a a is still a reason to do that,
仍然有一个原因去这样做，
because if you want to get the cost of the hardest stripes to do cheaper,
因为如果你想要以更低的成本完成最困难的任务，
right?
对的吗？
To be cheaper,
为了更便宜，
and still have almost proper performance compare basis as these.
并且在与这些基准相比几乎具有适当的性能。
But that's probably true today.
但这可能在今天是真实的。
But in a few years,
但是在几年之后，
again, if ss bs are going to drop at the cost of how these drives there is,
再次强调，如果固态硬盘（SSD）和机械硬盘（HDD）的价格下降，那么这些驱动器的成本会受到影响。
no reason for these optimization.
没有理由进行这些优化。
You have a symmetric block rights performance.
您拥有对称的块权限性能。
We know that.
我们知道。
And we learn about that.
我们会学习关于那个的内容。
You have where the limited lifetime in terms of rights, writing, rights.
您在这里提到了有关权利、写作和权利方面的有限寿命。
But I still need to be careful.
但是我仍然需要小心。
Average final rate is 6 years,
平均最终利率为6年。
life expenses between 9 and 10,
9点到10点之间的生活费用
11 years are actually better than hard these drives.
11年实际上比这些硬盘更好。
It's again the deal they are here.
他们又来了，这次是交易。
Ss ds had a battery in almost every respect.
Ss ds在几乎所有方面都有电池。
You need to be more careful.
你需要更加小心。
You need it's more complex.
你需要的是更复杂的东西。
The algorithms are more complex to go around these limitations
这些算法更复杂，以克服这些限制。
that the agents are very expensive,
代理商非常昂贵。
and you need to erase a page before writing it,
在写入之前，您需要擦除一页。
where you need to take into account the wearing of pages.
在这里，你需要考虑页面的磨损情况。
It's more expensive about the cost of dropping.
放弃的成本更高。
So the prices are dropping.
价格正在下降。
So is a question here,
这里有一个问题，
just wondering how much overhale generally is
只是想知道一般来说大修需要多长时间
there for the hybrid alternative system involving
因此，涉及混合替代系统的方案是这样的
both society and hardy stripes?
社会和困难条纹？
It seems like it would be a lot more complex keeping track going
跟踪进展似乎会更加复杂
between both in the same computer.
在同一台计算机之间。
It's more complex, but the way that you buy this like you buy that like,
这个更复杂，但购买方式就像购买那样。
it's like,
就像是，
is the same enclosure,
是相同的外壳。
the hardest drive.
最困难的驱动器。
They are not two different devices.
它们不是两个不同的设备。
You buy, like, it's like a device which you plug into your satire bus, right?
你购买的是一种设备，你将其插入你的讽刺总线中，对吗？
And like you'll buy a hardest drive or ssd and you buy this kind of highly devised.
你会购买一个最大容量的硬盘或固态硬盘，并购买这种高度发达的设备。
And inside the device,
设备内部
you hide all the complexity.
你隐藏了所有的复杂性。
You have ssd you have the hardest drive,
你有 SSD，你有最硬的硬盘。
and you have complex logic to deal and to use ssd basically like a cash
你需要处理复杂的逻辑来使用SSD，基本上就像一个缓存一样。
for the harvest stripes.
为了收获条纹。
Did answer your question, gilbert?
你的问题得到了回答，吉尔伯特？
It's complex, but it's hit up.
这很复杂，但是它已经开始了。
The complex is hit up announcements.
这个复杂的地方被公告所充斥。
How much story is due on mondays?
周一需要完成多少篇故事？
You now meet them too.
你现在也见到他们了。
But if you now we have a time between 5:00 and 6:67 pm on monday,
但是如果你现在知道我们在周一下午5:00到6:67之间有时间的话，
a meter to its wednesday between 7:00 and 9:00 pm please read
请在周三晚上7点至9点之间读取一下电表。
the updated proctor and guide.
更新的监考员和指南。
You can have an additional a cheat sheet for this exam.
你可以在这次考试中使用额外的备忘单。
Remember that this exam will cover everything from the beginning of the semester,
请记住，这次考试将涵盖整个学期的内容。
but we have more emphasized on the materials in the first meter.
但是我们在第一米的材料上更加强调。
The project is due next friday,
项目截止日期是下周五。
so next week it's a hard week,
所以下周是一个艰难的一周，
but it's again, after that, it will be easier.
但是再一次之后，会变得更容易。
Now let's switch gear.
现在让我们换个方向。
Any question now about a storage device is what we learn over the last
关于存储设备的任何问题，都是我们在上次学习中学到的内容吗？
and this lecture?
这节课呢？
Harvest drive and solid state drives.
收集驱动和固态硬盘。
Right now,
现在，
we are going to swiss gears,
我们要去瑞士的山区。
and we are going to talk about performance and how to model performance.
我们将讨论性能和如何建模性能。
If you saw this kind of even like device drivers are pretty complex,
如果你发现像设备驱动程序这样的事件非常复杂，
you get the request, you in queue,
你已收到请求，你已进入队列中，
the request because you may have multiple requests arriving
这个请求是因为你可能有多个请求同时到达。
at the same time yourselves,
同时，你们自己，
a request.
一个请求。
And by from the point of view of the per the program who made the request,
从发出请求的程序的角度来看，
he cares only about the entrant latency.
他只关心进入延迟。
But the center and latency is divided or support is divided
但是中心和延迟是分开的还是支持是分开的？
between multiple components.
在多个组件之间。
We are going to learn a little bit about how to model those.
我们将学习一些关于如何对其进行建模的知识。
And let's try first to define what are the metrics we care about.
让我们首先尝试定义我们关心的指标是什么。
The response time or latency is time to perform an operation is the end
响应时间或延迟是执行操作所需的时间。
to end time.
结束时间。
You have the bandwidth or throughput is the right to which you can perform
带宽或吞吐量是指你可以执行的权利。
operations operation per second for different devices.
不同设备的每秒操作次数。
See, the operation can be different, like, for instance,
看，操作可以是不同的，比如，例如，
a it's a different metric here.
这里使用的是不同的度量标准。
But all the metrics are over second.
但是所有的指标都超过了一秒钟。
It's some quantity over second like files.
这是一些每秒的数量，比如文件。
For files when you read and write is megabytes per second.
当你读取和写入文件时，速度以每秒兆字节计算。
For a network is megabytes per second, right?
对于网络来说，是以兆字节每秒（MB/s）计算的，对吗？
When you said megabytes is power of two, if you remember,
当你说到兆字节是二的幂时，如果你还记得的话，
megabyss for the network is power of ten like this.
网络的单位"兆字节"是以十的幂次来表示的。
So you like, for instance,
那么，比如说，你喜欢的东西是什么？
one megabyte for,
一个兆字节的容量为，
but one megabyte for files is one thousand twenty twenty four kilobytes.
但是对于文件来说，一兆字节等于一千零二十四千兆字节。
One megabit for network is 1,000,
网络中的一个兆比特是1,000,000个比特。
sorry, one megabit for network.
抱歉，网络速度为1兆比特。
What i'm saying?
我在说什么？
One megabyte for files.
一个兆字节的文件空间。
It's1,024 kilobytes.
这是1024千字节。
I I said correctly.
我是否说得正确。
One megabyte per second for network.
网络速度为每秒一兆字节。
It's 1,000 kilobits per second.
每秒1,000千比特。
And then you have giga flops operation per second,
然后你每秒拥有十亿次浮点运算操作。
floating point operation for second,
每秒的浮点运算次数
for automatic computation and things like that.
用于自动计算和类似的事情。
Then you have a startup or overhead.
那么你就有了创业或额外开销。
It's a time to initiate an operation.
现在是开始操作的时候了。
This can be think about like something like context reject.
这可以被理解为类似于上下文拒绝的情况。
I mostly,
我主要，
operation are roughly linear in the number of bytes.
操作的时间复杂度大致与字节数成线性关系。
So basically, what happens by so basically, for instance,
所以基本上，"so basically" 的意思是，例如，
you if you are going to the way you can model this operation,
如果你要去的话，你可以对这个操作进行建模。
there is an overhead or aa fixed cost to initiate the operation.
进行该操作会有一定的开销或固定成本。
You pay on that operation.
您需要支付该操作的费用。
No matter how much you transfer,
无论你转账多少金额，
then it's a variable cost and the variable cost is.
那么这是一个变动成本，变动成本是什么。
And how many bytes,
还有多少字节，
in this case you transfer over the bandwidth?
在这种情况下，您是通过带宽进行传输吗？
If you remember, we've seen this pretty very much in the last lecture.
如果你还记得的话，我们在上一堂课中已经非常详细地讲过这个了。
For hardest drives.
对于硬盘驱动器。
You remember, you have the overhead,
你记得，你有额外开销。
which was the sick time and rotational latency.
这是指病态时间和旋转延迟。
No matter how much you read or write on a disk,
无论您在磁盘上读取或写入多少数据，
you need to pay for that cost, right?
你需要支付那个费用，对吗？
When you do that read and write.
当你进行读取和写入操作时。
And then once you locate and you do that,
然后一旦你找到并完成这个任务，
the rest a sequential right read and write,
其余的是顺序的右读和写入。
then it's about how fast you are going to be able to repeat from the disk.
这取决于你能够从磁盘中重复读取的速度有多快。
And that is given by how fast is the dis rotating The rotation of the disk?
这取决于磁盘的旋转速度。
That is a variable part.
那是一个可变的部分。
You need more.
你需要更多。
It's going to take more time.
这将需要更多的时间。
This is a way to look at it.
这是一种看待它的方式。
Again.
再次。
Basically, you have the user thread,
基本上，你有用户线程，
which is going to initiate.
即将启动的是哪个？
And i'm input operation.
我是输入操作。
Then you have a queue,
那么你有一个队列，
you can have queue.
你可以使用队列。
This is can be in controller,
这可以在控制器中实现。
or it can be in the operating system.
或者它可以在操作系统中。
It depends on the implementation.
这取决于具体的实现方式。
It depends on the device.
这取决于设备。
But there is a cure along the way where the request started cured.
但在请求开始的过程中，有一种治愈方法。
If there are multiple requests at the same time,
如果同时有多个请求，
then it's a controller,
那么它就是一个控制器。
and then it's finally the io device, right?
然后最后是输入输出设备，对吗？
Io device service time, right?
是的，IO设备服务时间。
This is how long I got the request,
这是我收到请求的时间长度，
how long it takes to satisfy that request.
满足该请求需要多长时间。
The metrics here are response times,
这里的指标是响应时间，
and so put response time we saw in the previous slide,
因此，将我们在前一张幻灯片中看到的响应时间放入其中。
it's s plus n over b what is the bandwidth?
带宽是 s 加上 n 除以 b。
Now, the bandwidth is that require one, the bandwidth,
现在，带宽是需要的，带宽。
which one of the bandwidth we really care,
我们真正关心的带宽是哪一个？
and is from the from the user thread perspective.
并且是从用户线程的角度来看的。
It is that we call the effective bandwidth.
这就是我们所称的有效带宽。
Right?
对吗？
And the affecting bandwidth is when we are saying, like, for instance,
影响带宽的情况是，当我们说到，例如，
if you remember, like hardest drives,
如果你还记得的话，就像硬盘一样，
the circuit is very different when we are reading
当我们进行读取操作时，电路是非常不同的。
randomly random reads or sequential reads.
随机读取或顺序读取。
That is very different, if you remember.
那是非常不同的，如果你还记得的话。
And and that's effective bandwidth.
这就是有效带宽。
So effective boundaries for random breed is
随机繁殖的有效边界是什么？
much lower than effective boundaries for sequential rates.
远远低于顺序速率的有效边界。
The reason is and effective boundary is basically it is how many by sims
原因是有效边界基本上是指通过模拟的数量。
send iii read or operation I
发送 iii 读取或操作 I
performed over how long it took me to read these and bytes that I
我读完这些所花费的时间以及字节数。
don't perform an
不要执行
operations.
操作。
The time it took to perform this operation,
执行此操作所花费的时间，
this latency from the previous slide is s plus n over b or you can
这个延迟是从前一页得出的，公式为 s 加上 n 除以 b，或者你可以...
also a little bit of re factoring is b over one plus sp over n right?
也稍微重构一下，b等于1加上sp除以n对吗？
So now you can see, exactly right.
现在你可以看到，完全正确。
It's like,
就像是，
if you read only 1 byte,
如果你只读取1个字节，
this is the denominator will be dominated.
这个分母将会被主导。
This will be dominated by s by the overhead, right?
这将被开销主导，对吗？
Which is include controller time, queue, delay, and things like that.
这包括控制器时间、队列、延迟等等。
If you are going to have read a lot of bytes,
如果你要读取大量的字节，
this will be dominated by n actually,
这将主要由n主导。
the effective bandwidth becomes as similar with a bandwidth of the io device,
有效带宽与IO设备的带宽变得相似。
like,
喜欢，
or in the case of a hardest drive with a bandwidth of sequential access.
或者在具有顺序访问带宽的硬盘的情况下。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
We'll talk more about that plot.
我们会更详细地讨论那个情节。
You see, on the right hand side,
你看，右边的
the only thing and i'm going to repeat that a few times.
唯一的事情，我会重复几次。
The only thing to keep in mind is that this is the kind of curve you
需要记住的唯一一件事是，这是一种曲线类型，你
are going to see.
你们要去看什么。
This is on the xy axis.
这是在xy轴上。
You have the utilization,
你有利用率。
right?
对的？
How much utilization is about the load which is offered to the device,
负载对设备的利用率有多高？
the system over the capacity of the system.
系统超出了系统的容量。
Right?
对吗？
How much I can handle?
我能处理多少？
And if you on x axis,
如果你在x轴上，
you see the response, the y axis,
你看到了回应，Y轴。
you see the response time.
你看到了响应时间。
This is how it looks like initially is going.
这是最初的样子。
And the system is not very loudly.
而且系统声音不是很大。
You have very little loud.
你的声音很小。
You get very good performance response time is very good.
你的性能响应时间非常好。
But you try to grouse,
但你试图抱怨，
and after some point is going to shut up,
并且在某个时候会保持安静，
if the load is equal to the capacity of the system, actually,
如果负载等于系统的容量，实际上，
the response time can go to infinity,
响应时间可以无限增长，
right?
是的，正确的。
Can go extremely fast.
可以非常快速。
Right?
对吗？
This is the same, like, remember, it's like highway.
这是一样的，就像是，记住，就像是高速公路。
When the highway is free,
当高速公路畅通无阻时，
very late in the night or very early in the morning.
在深夜或清晨非常晚。
If you go very fast, right?
如果你走得很快，对吗？
As a speed like legal speed, hopefully, right?
希望是合法的速度，对吗？
And if,
如果，
on the other hand,
另一方面，
if you start like rush hour,
如果你开始像交通高峰时间一样忙碌，
right?
对的？
The delays can be shut up.
延迟可以被消除。
Right?
对吗？
And that's a big,
而且这是一个很大的，
obviously, is a big problem.
显然，这是一个大问题。
And then is the capacity of the system, right?
然后是系统的容量，对吗？
Because you're still out at the capacity of the system,
因为你仍然超出了系统的容量。
because eventually all the car still get home, right?
因为最终所有的车辆都会回家，对吗？
So it's not none of them is stuck indefinitely.
所以没有一个是无限期卡住的。
Let me give me 1 second.
让我给你一秒钟。
I think it's the sense of light.
我认为这是光的感觉。
Let me just start the light again.
让我重新启动一下灯。
Sounds good.
好的。
I need to move more contributor.
我需要吸引更多的贡献者。
So the factor to latency,
因此，延迟的因素是什么？
like I mentioned, this kind of s it's about harder control the
就像我之前提到的那样，这种情况更难控制。
the io service time,
IO服务时间
device service time, and so forth.
设备服务时间等等。
But the most interesting part,
但最有趣的部分是，
one of the most important things here is a queue,
这里最重要的一件事是队列。
right?
对的？
Because queue here, you have a lot of requests coming in.
因为队列在这里，你有很多请求进来。
You kill them, so you can spend a lot of time in the cure.
你杀死他们，这样你就可以花很多时间来治愈。
Actually, there is a response time shoots up.
实际上，响应时间出现了激增。
It's not because the device,
这不是因为设备的问题，
the aisle device time, service time,
通道设备时间，服务时间。
serving a request,
处理一个请求
still take the same amount of time.
仍然需要相同的时间。
So this is very important to remember the reasons the response time
所以记住响应时间的原因非常重要。
shows up is because a cure because they have more and more requests
出现的原因是因为需求越来越多，所以需要更多的解决方案。
as they have to wait for the previous request.
因为他们需要等待前一个请求。
To be said, it's like you go into a grocery store.
可以这样说，就好像你走进一家杂货店。
So the time it takes a clerk to serve a customer,
所以店员为顾客提供服务所需的时间，
doesn't depend on the queue size.
不依赖于队列大小。
Right?
对吗？
It still takes the same time.
仍然需要相同的时间。
Maybe if the queue is long,
如果队列很长的话，
maybe it's going even takes less because going to be hurry.
可能会花更少的时间，因为要赶快去。
But it's,
但是，
in logic, it ideally doesn't depend on the q size.
在逻辑上，理想情况下不应该依赖于队列大小。
However, if there are many people in the store,
然而，如果商店里有很多人，
you are going to eat more.
你要多吃一点。
Why?
为了方便中文用户理解和阅读，我会将英文内容翻译成中文。这样可以提供更好的帮助和支持。
Because the queue is longer.
因为队列更长。
One of the most interesting and relevant aspects,
其中最有趣和相关的方面之一，
it's a queue is of a system is a queue,
这是一个系统的队列。
and this is what they are going to analyze a little bit.
这是他们打算稍微分析一下的内容。
This is a way you typically present.
这是你通常的演示方式。
You can model the system,
你可以对系统进行建模，
you have arrivals and rivals, use that request,
你有到达者和竞争者，请使用该请求。
which arrives like read requests, write requests, packets.
这些请求包括读请求、写请求和数据包。
That can be packets which arrive at the outer and things like that.
这可能是到达外部的数据包之类的东西。
Then you serve this request like the server.
那么你就像服务器一样处理这个请求。
You send the data out,
你发送数据出去，
you serve the reads and writes and things like that.
你负责处理读取、写入等操作。
Then you have 2 times the queue,
那么你有两倍的队列。
which is a queuing time,
这是一个排队时间。
and ts is a serving time.
ts是服务时间。
And the response time is basically dq plus ds the queuing time
响应时间基本上是等待时间dq加上排队时间ds。
for the service time.
关于服务时间。
Now you have another one.
现在你有另一个任务。
It's ta which is in this is obviously you have here in this figure.
这是一个显然在这个图中的TA。
It's on the x axis.
它在x轴上。
You have the time.
你有时间。
And the ta is an inter arrival time.
而 TA 是到达时间间隔。
Basically,
基本上，
in the difference between two consecutive between the arrival
在两个连续到达之间的差异中
of two consecutive requests,
连续两个请求
this is the arrival.
这是到达。
Now, on the y axis,
现在，在y轴上，
which is not shown,
未显示的是
I should show here.
我应该在这里展示。
If you go down,
如果你倒下来，
you move from down is a time it takes.
你从下面移动需要花费的时间。
It's basically,
基本上，
it's a response time.
这是响应时间。
Right?
对吗？
So what this shows here is that,
这里显示的是，
sorry,
对不起，
what it shows here is basically,
这里显示的基本上是，
you have d queue is like,
你有一个类似于队列的数据结构，
it's a time you spend in the queue.
这是你在队列中等待的时间。
Then ds is a time you spend to service ps to service that request.
然后 ds 是你花费的时间来为 ps 提供服务并处理该请求。
After a while you have another request,
过了一会儿，你有另一个请求。
which is skew is very little.
偏斜非常小。
Here is a queue.
这是一个队列。
It's empty.
它是空的。
But it's still probably a time.
但这可能仍然需要一些时间。
Because you still need probably maybe to even if it's one element in the cure,
因为即使在治疗中只有一个元素，你可能仍然需要它。
you need to incur it and then get it out of the cure,
你需要承担它，然后将其治愈。
just checking whether the queue is empty.
只是检查队列是否为空。
So there is still a little bit of time you are going to spend.
所以你还需要花一点时间。
Right?
对吗？
But here you are dominated by the service time.
但在这里，你受到服务时间的支配。
And you see,
你看，
whenever if you have a new request,
每当您有新的请求时，
at least in this example,
至少在这个例子中，
you are going to the queue something.
你要将某物放入队列。
Every response time that it could,
尽可能地回应时间
the response time on february quest is going to take the same time.
二月份的请求响应时间将会保持不变。
But now let's do,
但现在让我们开始吧，
so let's introduce a few more metrics.
那么让我们介绍几个更多的度量指标。
So a few more metrics here are basically the service rate is
这里还有一些指标，基本上服务速率是
basically is like how
基本上就像是如何
many operations you can perform per second.
你可以每秒执行许多操作。
Right?
对吗？
Basically, this is one over ts right?
基本上，这是一个除以 ts 的操作对吧？
It's like, if, for instance,
就好像，例如，
if it takes me to serve a request,
如果处理一个请求需要花费我的时间，
it takes 10 million seconds to serve a request.
处理一个请求需要1000万秒。
How many I can do per second?
我每秒钟能做多少个？
1 seconds over 10 million seconds is 100,
1秒钟是100万秒的1/10000000。
then its arrival rate.
然后是它的到达率。
And this is one over ta right?
这是一个右边的一个吗？
This has request per second.
这是每秒的请求数。
The request per second.
每秒请求数。
It's the same, right?
是一样的，对吗？
It's like if I am getting every one request,
就好像我在接收每一个请求一样
every 20 millisecond,
每20毫秒，
then the lambda,
然后是 lambda，
which is request per second.
每秒请求数。
It's 1/20 million seconds,
这是一千二百万分之一秒。
1 second over 20 million seconds is 50, right?
1秒钟超过2000万秒是50，对吗？
And then its utilization utilization is the arrival rate over the service rate.
然后它的利用率是到达率除以服务率。
Or if you plug in this equation,
或者如果你将这个方程代入计算，
the formula for the service rate and arrival rate,
服务率和到达率的公式是：
you are going to get the service time over the arrival time.
你将获得服务时间超过到达时间的服务。
Right?
对吗？
Basically, what is this saying is that, for instance,
基本上，这句话的意思是，例如，
if you have the arrival time,
如果你有到达时间的话，
it's 20 millisecond.
这是20毫秒。
The service time is 10 million seconds.
服务时间为1000万秒。
Then you are going to have 10 million seconds over 20 million seconds.
那么你将拥有2000万秒中的1000万秒。
It's 0.5 utilization will be50%,
它的利用率为0.5将是50%。
which kind of makes sense, right?
这在某种程度上是有道理的，对吧？
If I have one new request arriving every 20 millisecond and one request,
如果我每20毫秒收到一个新的请求，并且有一个请求，
it takes me to process one request,
处理一个请求需要花费我一些时间，
10 million seconds.
1000万秒。
This means that for each request,
这意味着对于每个请求，
i'm going to spend 10 millisecond and i'm going to wait
我将花费10毫秒并等待。
another 10 millisecond to get the new request.
再等待10毫秒来获取新的请求。
And I am going to be free half of my time.
我将有一半的时间是空闲的。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
What happens on lambda is greater than the mu,
当λ大于μ时会发生什么？
and the arrival rate is greater than the survey.
到达率大于调查的情况。
The rate.
速率。
What do you think it happens?
你认为会发生什么？
It's a good question.
这是一个很好的问题。
If it's a for short interval of time, what is a burst?
如果是指短时间间隔，"burst" 是什么意思？
Then you are going to have the cure to absorb that burst.
那么你将会有解决办法来吸收那个突发情况。
The q delay were going to increase.
q的延迟将会增加。
If it's longer is for a long time,
如果它更长时间，则表示很长时间了。
is it just average arrival rate is greater than the average service rate?
这是指平均到达率是否大于平均服务率？
Then the queue will grow indefinitely.
那么队列将无限增长。
The system is called to be in a stable state.
系统被称为处于稳定状态。
In general,
一般来说，
what we are going to analyze now in this lecture are our systems which are
在本课程中，我们将要分析的是我们的系统，这些系统是
a stable means
一个稳定的手段
that the arrival rate is not greater than the service rate.
到达率不应大于服务率。
Good.
好的。
This is basically tells you is about if ds over
这基本上是在告诉你如果ds超过了什么
da it's small,
嗒，这很小。
then we are fine.
那我们没问题了。
And the queue time,
还有队列时间，
the queuing delay is slow.
排队延迟较慢。
But after some.,
但是经过一段时间后，
if you are going to get one, this is loud.
如果你打算买一个，这个会很吵。
You see, the loud is for this plot from 0 to 1.
你看，这个图表的横轴是从0到1。
This is the sa over da right?
这是源地址覆盖目的地址对吗？
Before one is fine.
之前一个就可以了。
It grows, but it grows a little bit.
它在增长，但增长得很少。
But if you are going to go over one,
但是如果你要超过一个，
then it's going to shut up.
那么它就会安静下来。
Right?
对吗？
This is a cure delay.
这是一个治疗延迟。
It can be unbounded.
它可以是无界的。
This is the answer to your question.
这是对你问题的答案。
Gilbert,
吉尔伯特，
if the arrival rate is greater than the service rate,
如果到达率大于服务率，
then the cure will grow unbounded.
那么治愈将无限增长。
Now, let's see how the requests that i've been abused.
现在，让我们看一下我所受到的滥用请求。
And let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
Here on the vertical axis,
这里是纵轴，
I have q depths on the horizontal axis against the time.
我在水平轴上有q个深度随时间变化。
Here, basically, ii see here the queue depth.
这里，基本上，我在这里看到了队列深度。
I'm going to have the first requesting the queue.
我将会将第一个请求放入请求队列中。
It's empty.
它是空的。
It's going to be service immediately.
将立即提供服务。
This is where it's going to be.
这就是它将要放置的地方。
Server is the server,
服务器是指服务器，
the timeline for the server.
服务器的时间线。
It's a rather, I get the queue, I get the request,
这是一个相当简单的问题，我已经理解了队列和请求。
i'm going to serve it here.
我会在这里为您服务。
But now I get the second request.
但是现在我收到了第二个请求。
If i'm getting the second request,
如果我收到第二个请求，
I am going to have to cure and cure it because the survey is already
我将不得不治疗和治愈它，因为调查已经进行了。
it's satisfying the previous request.
已满足之前的请求。
And now I get a new request.
现在我收到了一个新的请求。
So a new request, again,
所以又有一个新的请求，再次。
I need to cure it.
我需要治疗它。
Right now, I have two requests in the cure again on the vertical axis down.
现在，我有两个请求在垂直轴向下方进行治疗。
You have the size of the cure.
你有治愈的尺寸。
Also I have two in the cure right now.
我现在有两个正在治疗中。
Now I get another one.
现在我又收到另一个。
So it's again the first request hasn't finished, being serviced.
所以第一个请求还没有完成，正在被处理。
So the cure is increasing by another.
所以治愈人数又增加了。
Her one request.
她的一个请求。
I have three requests in the queue.
我有三个请求在队列中。
Now I don't get anything more.
现在我什么都不明白了。
Right?
对吗？
If I don't anything more,
如果我没有其他要做的事情，
i'm going to start the set of being say it's a fivefold.
我将开始这一系列的说法，它是五倍的。
So i'm going to sell the first requesting the queues a wide request.
所以我要将第一个请求队列中的一个宽请求出售。
While I serve the wide request like you,
当我像你一样服务广大的请求时，
I still have two requests in the queue.
我还有两个请求在队列中。
The light blew on,
灯亮了，
and they're all ranger on.
他们都穿上了护林员制服。
Then when I say I when I finish serving this request,
那么当我完成处理这个请求时，
i'm going to serve the orange request.
我将处理橙色请求。
Finally is a light blue request.
最后是一个浅蓝色的请求。
This is what happens.
这是发生的情况。
And I have a new request and things like that.
我有一个新的请求和类似的事情。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
The point here is that even the utilization is slow,
这里的重点是即使利用率很低，
even in the average arrival rate,
即使在平均到达率下，
is lower than the service rate,
低于服务速率
much lower level.
更低层次的。
You can still have occasional burst.
你仍然可以偶尔有爆发。
A lot of events,
很多事件，
a lot of operation alive at the same time.
同时有很多操作正在进行。
It's like rush hour,
就像是高峰时间，
right over the entire duration of a day.
在整个一天的时间内。
The arrival of the number of cars on the highway is
公路上汽车数量的到达
significantly lower than the capacity of the highway.
远远低于高速公路的容量。
There are some bursts in rush hours is a number of cars.
在高峰时段会有一些车辆的突发增加。
It's almost at capacity.
它快要达到容量上限了。
And then you experience large effects.
然后你会经历很大的影响。
How do you model the birthday arrival?
你如何建模生日到达的情况？
Now, there is a lot of mathematical models,
现在有很多数学模型，
but one of the most elegant one,
但其中最优雅的一个，
it's is poisson distribution or distribution.
这是泊松分布还是其他分布？
Exponential distribution.
指数分布。
This is f of x is slumber where lambda is the average arrival rate,
这里的 f(x) 是一个休眠函数，其中 lambda 是平均到达率。
in this case,
在这种情况下，
or an average mean for that distribution times e power minus
该分布的平均值乘以e的负次幂
lx this is how it looks like.
lx 这是它的外观。
This f of fx and this is a lambda.
这是 f 的 fx，这是一个 lambda。
It's actually the mean arrival rate.
实际上是平均到达率。
So the mean arrival rate for this distribution,
这个分布的平均到达率是多少？
it's one over lambda.
它是 lambda 的倒数。
I'm actually lambda.
我实际上是lambda。
I'm taking back.
我收回了。
The lambda represent the inter arrival time between the events I
lambda代表了事件之间的到达时间间隔
arrival time in sandova lambda.
到达时间在桑多瓦的λ。
And is a nice thing about this.
这是一个很好的事情。
The exponential distribution is it is what is called memory less.
指数分布被称为"无记忆性"分布。
Memory less means that the future doesn't depend on the past,
"Memoryless"在计算机操作系统中意味着未来的情况不依赖于过去的情况。
right?
对的？
And is counter intuitive,
这是一个反直觉的事情。
because you are not used with that.
因为你不习惯那样做。
This will say, and maybe sometime this happens,
这句话的意思是，也许有时候会发生这种情况。
if you go,
如果你走了，
if you arrive at the station like bus station,
如果你到达车站，比如公交车站，
how long it takes for the next train to arrive doesn't depend
下一班火车到达需要多长时间并不取决于
of when the previous train arrived,
关于前一班火车到达的时间，
whether it arrived.
是否已经到达。
The last minute was that he just leaves the station where it was 15 minutes
最后一分钟是他刚离开车站，而那个车站停留了15分钟。
ago.
之前。
This is what?
这是什么？
But because it's memorized,
但是因为它是被记住的，
it's much easier to model.
这个模型要简单得多。
Right?
对吗？
It also says,
它还说，
if you look at this plot,
如果你看一下这个图表，
that this means that a lot of events which are arriving in burst,
这意味着很多事件会以突发方式到达。
rise at interval between them is short.
它们之间的间隔很短。
There are some also very long intervals between events.
事件之间也有一些非常长的间隔。
So if you look at the events on the timeline that are burst of events
所以如果你看一下时间线上的事件，它们是一系列事件的爆发。
arriving together,
一起到达，
inter arrival between these event is small,
这些事件之间的到达间隔很短，
and then you have long pauses,
然后你会有很长的停顿，
right?
对的？
Long gaps.
长时间间隔。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
You did learn an exponential distribution?
你学过指数分布吗？
Ii hope in some of your math classes,
我希望在你的一些数学课程中，
right?
对的？
Or statistic classes.
或者统计课程。
Okay?
好的？
And now,
现在，
with this distribution is,
使用这个分发版本，
what are the main mode matrix?
主模式矩阵是什么？
My one of the most important matrix is a mean.
我最重要的矩阵之一是均值矩阵。
Obviously, the mean of the distribution,
显然，分布的均值是指数据的平均值。
how to compute them in,
如何进行计算？
like,
喜欢，
it's an integral or the sound you pay for the discrete distribution
这是一个离散分布中所支付的声音的积分。
of the p of t what is the probability that
在给定条件下，t的概率是多少？
event happens that time at t what is the probability that you
在时间t发生的事件的概率是多少？
are going to have?
你们要开会吗？
In this case?
在这种情况下？
For instance, an arrival after exact in exactly titan units.
例如，一个在恰好在恰好的titan单位之后到达的事件。
And then you are going to multiply with the t because the inter arrival time.
然后你将与t相乘，因为这是到达时间间隔。
Right?
对吗？
This is the mean.
这是平均值。
Right?
对吗？
If you have this variance of the square of the standard deviation,
如果你有标准差的平方的方差，
which is you multiply its sum of p of t multiplied by t squared minus m squared.
这是将t的p的和乘以t的平方减去m的平方。
And m is against the mean.
而 m 是指反对平均值。
P is about how long the entire arrival p which
P是关于整个到达过程的时间长度。
happen is probability p of t and then you square coefficient of variance,
发生的概率是p，然后将方差系数平方。
which is a sigma squared by the mean square.
这是方差除以均方的结果。
I'm not going to derive this to you.
我不会为你推导这个。
I'm going to derive something more interesting to you.
我将为您推导出更有趣的内容。
You are supposed to know from some of your previous classes.
你应该从你之前的一些课程中知道。
If not.
如果不是的话。
This are just the formula you can write on your cheat sheet.
这些只是你可以写在作弊纸上的公式。
But typically we are going to give you, if I am going,
但通常情况下，如果我去的话，我们会给你
we are going to ask you in a problem.
我们将在一个问题中向您提问。
But the most important things here is to look at the value of sea,
但这里最重要的是看海的价值。
the sea capture, the burst mess.
海洋的捕获，爆发的混乱。
It turns out if c is zero,
原来如果c为零，
there is no variance.
没有差异。
This also means the variance is zero square squared of standard deviation,
这也意味着方差是标准差的平方的平方。
which means that you have the inter arrival between two events,
这意味着你有两个事件之间的到达间隔时间。
between two requests is the same.
两个请求之间的时间间隔是相同的。
Then if c is one,
那么如果 c 是一个的话，
this means that you have exponential distribution.
这意味着你有指数分布。
Is a memory less distribution.
这是一个无记忆分布。
Completely random, doesn't depend on the past.
完全随机，不依赖于过去。
If c is 1.5,
如果c是1.5，
you have even adversarial distributions.
你甚至有对抗性分布。
The majority of sikhs say, for instance,
大多数锡克教徒表示，例如，
or the majority of the inter arrival times are much smaller than the average.
或者大多数的到达间隔时间远小于平均值。
The more c increases,
c增加的越多，
the more birthday.
越多的生日。
You have the distribution,
你已经获得了分发版本。
meaning a lot of events coming,
意思是有很多事件即将发生。
a lot of requests coming together,
同时出现了很多请求。
and then long gaps.
然后是长时间的间隔。
And a fuel is obviously the more person, as you have,
燃料显然是更多的人，就像你一样，
the larger the cube will be.
立方体越大。
That is during these events.
那是在这些事件发生期间。
Right?
对吗？
If there is no variance,
如果没有方差，
and if your third load is lower than the service capacity,
如果你的第三次负载低于服务能力，
than you have no cure,
那你就无法治愈了。
let's talk more about king's theory.
让我们更多地谈谈金斯理论。
The queuing theory is very simple.
排队论非常简单。
You have to make some assumption about the distributions.
你需要对分布做一些假设。
You have to make some assumptions about how long it takes to serve the request.
你需要对请求的处理时间做一些假设。
What is the distribution to serve a request?
什么是用于处理请求的分发方式？
What is the distribution of arrivals?
到达的分布是什么？
And based on this,
根据这个，
then you are going to get some formula which will give you
然后你将得到一些公式，这些公式将给出你
the service response time as a change between delay.
服务响应时间是延迟变化的一种表现形式。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
Okay.
好的。
Before talking more about this queuing and giving results
在进一步讨论这个排队和给出结果之前
formulas about response time and everything,
关于响应时间和其他方面的公式，
let's go through this law.
让我们来仔细阅读这个法律。
Little law is called,
Little定律被称为
it's a very powerful law.
这是一项非常强大的法律。
It's very simple, deceptive, simple,
这非常简单，具有欺骗性，简单。
and very general.
非常普遍的。
This is what it says.
这是它的内容。
He says you have a bunch of arrivals,
他说你有一大堆到达的人。
and which are served by a system,
以及由系统提供的服务，
a bunch of requests coming to a system.
一堆请求发送到系统中。
They are serving the system.
他们正在为系统提供服务。
And what is the average mean of?
这里的"average mean"是指什么的平均值？
What is the average arrivals for the request?
请求的平均到达次数是多少？
What is the average service for the requests?
请求的平均服务时间是多少？
And what little law is giving you is how many,
而法律给予你的只是多少，
on the average,
平均而言，
how many requests are waiting in the queue to be set?
队列中有多少个请求正在等待被处理？
That's all.
就这些。
And the formula is a number of requests.
公式是请求的数量。
Here I pick jobs.
这里我选择工作。
It's sequel to the mean arrival time,
这是到达时间的续集。
lambda time,
the response time,
响应时间
mean response time.
平均响应时间。
This is what it is.
就是这样。
That's it.
And the beauty of it is that this is true regardless of the structure
而且美妙的是，无论结构如何，这都是真实的。
of the arrivals.
到达的人数。
How it is a burst doesn't depend on the distribution.
一个进程的执行时间不取决于其分布情况。
Doesn't depend on the distribution of the arrival.
不依赖于到达的分布。
Doesn't it depends on distribution of the service style,
这不是取决于服务风格的分布吗？
because the results hold for the means.
因为这些结果适用于平均值。
Right?
对吗？
It does assume, though,
尽管如此，它确实假设了
that their rivals are not larger,
他们的竞争对手并不更大，
the arrival rate is no larger than mean arrival rate is not larger than this.
到达率不会超过平均到达率。
Mean service right here.
这里提供的是优质的服务。
It's an example.
这是一个例子。
Just to give you the to capture that intuition on x you have times,
只是为了让你能够捕捉到关于x的直觉，你需要乘以多少次。
let's say you have a new job or request.
假设你有一份新的工作或请求。
For some reason here,
由于某种原因，这里
iii put jobs coming to the system and being serviced.
我将作业放入系统并进行服务。
You have one job every second,
你每秒钟有一个工作任务。
so this is deterministic arrival.
所以这是确定性到达。
Everyone, every second, you have a new job.
每个人，每一秒钟，你都有一个新的工作。
Exactly.
没错。
Every second.
每秒钟。
Any jobs takes to serve.
任何工作都需要服务。
5 seconds is what you have, right?
你有5秒钟的时间，对吗？
You have the first job starts here, you set 5 seconds,
你有第一个任务从这里开始，你设置了5秒。
the second job starts set 5 seconds and so forth.
第二个任务开始设置为5秒，以此类推。
Now, how many of the jobs you have in the system at any given time?
现在，在系统中您有多少个作业？
You can draw a line and the number of jobs you have in the system.
你可以画一条线来表示系统中的作业数量。
It's the number of jobs this line is going to intersect.
这是该线将要相交的作业数量。
And how many have five?
有多少个是五个？
What is the formula saying?
这个公式在说什么？
Number of jobs, a very number of jobs in the system.
系统中的作业数量非常多。
It's equal with the average or the mean arrival rate to just 1 times
这等于平均到达率或平均到达次数的1倍。
the mean service response time,
平均服务响应时间
which is five.
这是五。
It's fine.
没问题。
Let me try to derive this formula for you.
让我试着为您推导这个公式。
Okay.
好的。
Let's say now we are going to be general,
假设现在我们要进行一般性的讨论，
right?
对的？
The jobs can arrive at any time.
作业可以随时到达。
They can take any amount of time to be into that are going to be in the system.
它们可能需要任意长的时间才能进入系统。
Let's talk.
让我们聊聊吧。
L of I is the response time of job I and n of t is a number of jobs
L of I 是作业 I 的响应时间，n of t 是作业的数量
in the system at time t
在时间t的系统中
this is n of t at this particular time.
这是在特定时间的第n个t。
You want to see what is the system occupancy?
您想查看系统的占用情况吗？
How many, on the average,
平均来说，有多少个？
what is the number of jobs in the system?
系统中的作业数量是多少？
This n the average of n and n of d this is what you want to compute.
这是你想要计算的 n 和 d 的平均值。
The average of n of d before this, remember, is what I want to get.
我想要得到的是之前的 n 个 d 的平均值。
Now, let's do some a little bit of math.
现在，让我们做一些简单的数学题。
Let's assume,
假设我们
for the simplicity that the height of one of these things, jobs,
为了简单起见，我们将这些事物中的一个称为"作业"，
which I represented here, each one,
我在这里代表的是每一个。
really, the n of t zero n is represents the height of this shape,
实际上，t零n的n代表了这个形状的高度。
the blue shape.
蓝色的形状。
Let's say, in this case,
假设，在这种情况下，
the hype is forced.
这种炒作是被迫的。
You have four jobs in the system.
你在系统中有四个任务。
Right?
对吗？
Now, the area of each of these boxes is what?
现在，这些盒子的面积是多少？
I so phi, its ally, the length,
我很抱歉，我无法理解你的问题。请提供更多的上下文或详细说明你需要翻译的英文句子。
is how long it takes.
需要多长时间。
The job responds time for that particular job.
该特定作业的响应时间。
I times one,
我乘以一，
because we said that by convention,
因为我们说过，按照惯例，
we say that the height is one.
我们说高度为一。
The area s is s one,
面积 s 是 s 的一个单位。
the total area here,
这里的总面积是多少？
for these all the jobs within the time capital t it's s one plus s
对于在时间t内的所有工作，s是一个加一的值。
two plus csk
两加 csk
it's equal to its l one plus l two plus lk because si it's equal is
它等于它的L1加上L2再加上LK，因为SI等于它相等。
li times one.
李乘以一。
It's equal is li and why do I do this?
它的等于是li，为什么我要这样做？
Right?
对吗？
Now?
现在吗？
What I want to compute this to cure?
我想计算这个来治愈什么？
Remember that our average pure copenhacy is, what is this?
请记住，我们的平均纯酸度是什么意思？
It's this area over t that is not ending.
这个区域在 t 上没有结束。
I have this shape which I have this area.
我有一个形状，它有这个面积。
And I need to divide on the length of the area,
我需要根据区域的长度进行划分。
which is still, in this case,
在这种情况下，仍然是
to get to the average height of the area.
计算该地区的平均身高。
The n average,
平均值 n
the average number of jobs in the system is the average height of the shape,
系统中作业的平均数量是形状的平均高度。
which is s over p but now we know that s is l of one plus l of two plus l
现在我们知道s是l1加上l2加上l3。
of k over d now,
现在的 k 除以 d。
now is the beauty of it.
现在就是它的美妙之处。
I need to do only the one thing I need to divide by n total and
我只需要做一件事，就是将总数除以n。
multiply with n total.
乘以n的总和。
Right?
对吗？
And total is another number of jobs which arrived during this time being
总数是在此期间到达的另一个作业数量。
our service during this time.
在这段时间内，我们的服务。
It's the same equation,
这是同一个方程。
the equation from the previous one.
从前一个方程式中得出的方程式。
But i'm going to divide by n total.
但是我要总共除以n。
I'm now going to multiply by n total and total.
我现在要将总数乘以n。
In this example.
在这个例子中。
It will be k right?
没问题，没关系。
Because what I showed here like it.
因为我展示的东西很喜欢。
But now I just reverted one,
但是现在我只是撤销了一个。
but is the same thing,
但是这是同样的事情。
is n total over p plus l one plus lk over n total.
n总数超过p加l再加lk除以n总数。
But here is the things right now.
但是现在的情况是这样的。
What is n total over t I have
n总数是多少，t是我拥有的数量。
n total jobs arriving during their time t in total over t it's the average.
在时间t内总共到达的作业数量n，总共花费的时间t，那么平均每个作业的到达速率为n/t。
It's how many?
这是多少？
It's n total over t it's arrival rate mean arrival rate.
这是关于到达率的信息，n是总数，t是时间，它表示平均到达率。
If I have one, if I tell you I have 100 jobs and they arrived in10 seconds,
如果我有一个问题，如果我告诉你我有100个任务，并且它们在10秒内到达，
right?
对的？
And I ask you,
我问你，
what is the rivalry?
竞争是什么？
What do you say?
你说什么？
100 over 10 seconds is ten jobs per second.
100个任务在10秒内是每秒10个任务。
This is lambda.
这是 lambda。
What is l one plus lk over n dot?
l one plus lk over n dot 是什么意思？
L one is the average response time for a job.
L1是作业的平均响应时间。
L two is a very response time of the second job.
L2是第二个作业的响应时间非常短。
If I had all these jobs up,
如果我把所有这些工作加起来，
the response time of all the jobs,
所有作业的响应时间
if I sum up the average response time of all jobs,
如果我将所有作业的平均响应时间相加，
and I divide by the number of jobs,
然后我除以作业的数量，
what do I get?
我能得到什么？
The average response time?
平均响应时间是多少？
Here you are the average occupancy or the average number of jobs in the system.
这里是系统的平均占用率或平均作业数量。
It's equal with the average arrival rate of the jobs plus at times, sorry,
这等于作业的平均到达率加上时间的和，抱歉，
the average response time of a job.
作业的平均响应时间。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay.
好的。
So again, I ii want to emphasize like this is a great,
所以再次强调，这是一个很棒的，
a very elegant law,
一个非常优雅的法律
because it's so simple.
因为它非常简单。
And yet is so general.
然而，"And yet" 是如此泛泛而言。
Again, doesn't make any assumption of distribution.
再次强调，不对分布做任何假设。
You need only to know the average arrival rate and average response time.
你只需要知道平均到达率和平均响应时间。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay?
好的？
Now let's do a little bit of hearing theory.
现在让我们来了解一些听觉理论。
And unfortunately, and I apologize here.
很不幸，我在这里向您道歉。
I am going to give you some results.
我将给你一些结果。
I'm not going to derive anymore.
我不会再推导了。
So hopefully you enjoy the previous derivation.
希望你喜欢之前的推导过程。
But let's talk a little bit about that about this to give you some queuing results,
但是让我们稍微谈谈这个，以给你一些排队的结果。
queuing theory results.
排队论的结果。
First of all, like I mentioned,
首先，就像我之前提到的，
here, we only assume that the system is what we call in equilibrium,
在这里，我们只假设系统处于我们所称的平衡状态下，
which is Basically the number the arrival rate is not larger,
基本上，到达率不会太大。
is no larger than the service site.
不超过服务站点的大小。
We also assume that the cure has no limits.
我们还假设治愈没有限制。
So therefore, we don't rob requests.
因此，我们不会拦截请求。
Okay?
好的？
Let's assume that the time between two arrivals is random and is memorabulous,
假设两次到达之间的时间是随机的，并且是不可预测的。
it's exponentially distributed when the time inter arrival time between
当到达时间间隔之间的时间间隔呈指数分布时
successive requests,
连续的请求
it's exponentially distributed.
它是指数分布的。
We are saying that arrival is for us all.
我们在说到达对我们所有人来说都是必然的。
By the way,
顺便说一下，
if you hear that arrival rate,
如果你听到到达率，
lambda service rate is mu one over the t survey.
Lambda服务率是mu除以t的倒数。
This is ATS previously we thoughts denoted by ps is that time yourself,
这是 ATS，之前我们认为用 ps 表示的是时间自身。
the request.
请求。
So you have lambda mean number of arriving request,
所以你有一个表示到达请求的平均值的 λ 值。
customer jobs per second.
每秒的客户作业数。
Meantime to serve as a customer,
同时作为一名顾客服务。
it's say, m squared coefficient of areas of variance.
这句话的意思是，m的平方是方差的系数。
This is one.
这是一个。
In the case.
在这种情况下。
Remember, in the case of exponential distribution,
请记住，在指数分布的情况下，
mu is a service rate that one of the TS time to service at request.
mu是一个服务速率，表示TS时间内处理请求的速度。
Utilization again,
再次提到利用率，
that you saw the formula is a number is arrival rate
你看到的公式是一个数字，表示到达率。
over the mean arrival rate over mean service rate,
平均到达率除以平均服务率
which is lambda over mu or lambda time.
是lambda除以mu还是lambda乘以mu？
Deserve I hear?
我值得听吗？
I just replace mere definition,
我只是替换了简单的定义。
which is one of the over the service time.
这是超过服务时间的其中之一。
Now, and if you do that,
现在，如果你这样做的话，
you get the utilization its arrival rate times I service time.
你可以通过将到达率乘以服务时间来计算利用率。
What do you want to compute?
你想要计算什么？
Time is spending the queue.
时间在队列中消耗。
That's what I want to compute.
这就是我想要计算的。
We also want to compute the length of the queue.
我们还想计算队列的长度。
What is the length of the queue?
队列的长度是多少？
The length of the cure is lambda of QQ because the system here is a cure.
治愈的长度是QQ的lambda，因为这里的系统是一个治愈。
This is what I'm saying.
这就是我要说的。
The system here is a cure,
这里的系统是一种治疗方法，
right?
对的？
You can apply little law to the cure itself,
你可以将小定律应用于治疗本身。
or you can apply to the entire system.
或者你可以应用到整个系统。
Here is for the cure yourself.
这是为了自我治愈。
Okay.
好的。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
Like I said, when you have exponential distribution for the arrival rates,
就像我说的，当到达率服从指数分布时，
inter arrival rates for the requests,
请求的到达间隔率
this is also called poisson arrival process.
这也被称为泊松到达过程。
We assume here that we have one server,
我们在这里假设我们有一个服务器，
right?
对的？
We can have us, there are scenarios,
我们可以有我们自己的情景。
and you have multiple servers,
而且你有多个服务器，
and you send the request to if one server sells a request to consider it,
并且你发送请求给一个服务器，如果有一个服务器接受请求，则将其视为销售请求。
send a request, another server.
发送一个请求到另一个服务器。
And it's memorized service.
这是一个记忆化的服务。
So again,
所以，再次，
let's assume that the service distribution,
假设服务分布，
it's also exponential.
这也是指数级的。
It's memory bus.
这是内存总线。
This system with poisson arrival process,
这个系统具有泊松到达过程，
memory said memory less, service time,
内存说内存不足，服务时间。
and one server is called mm one cure.
其中一个服务器被称为mm one cure。
It's again, one server,
又是一个服务器，
inter arrival times are exponentially distributed.
到达时间间隔服从指数分布。
Service time are exponentially distributed.
服务时间服从指数分布。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
the queuing time,
排队时间
it's equal with the service time
它等于服务时间
times u over one minus u what u is activation.
u是激活函数的输入，times u over one minus u可以翻译为u除以1减去u。
Now, for general distribution,
现在，为了普遍分发，
if you have the service distribution,
如果你有服务分发，
if the service time is a general distribution.
如果服务时间是一个一般分布。
And for that,
为此，
one only the variance,
只有方差。
the square root of variance,
方差的平方根
the c then this is a formula.
这是一个公式，其中的"c"表示某个变量。
It's very similar formula.
这是非常相似的公式。
One over, let me just move.
一会儿，让我先移动一下。
It's service time times one over two plus one one plus c this is, again,
这是服务时间的一半加上1再加上c，再重复一次。
square root of a square of variance times 11 over 1 minus 2.
方差的平方根乘以11除以1减2。
Is it important?
这个重要吗？
Take away from here.
离开这里。
This equation is a very important aspect here.
这个方程在这里是一个非常重要的方面。
Is this fact?
这是事实吗？
Is this 1 over 1 minus you?
这是 1 除以 (1 减去你) 吗？
Why it is important?
为什么这很重要？
Because this tells you when the utilization is small,
因为这告诉你当利用率很低时，
this factory is small, right?
这个工厂很小，对吗？
It's it's basically one u over one if u is very small.
如果u非常小，那么它基本上是1除以u。
But what happens to the utilization approach is what?
利用率方法是什么意思？
Which is a kiva land with a service, right?
这是一个有服务的基地，对吗？
A several arrival, right?
是多个到达吗？
Approaching the service, right?
是要接近服务吗？
What happens?
发生了什么事情？
It
这是一个不完整的句子，请提供更多的上下文。
gets very large.
变得非常大。
The cube becomes very large.
这个立方体变得非常大。
Another important aspect here,
这里还有另一个重要方面，
this is food for thought,
这是一种值得思考的食物。
is something which is not intuitive, either.
这也是一件不直观的事情。
If you goes close to one,
如果你靠近其中一个，
although it's not yet one,
尽管现在还不是一个
the queuing time goes to infinity.
排队时间趋近于无穷大。
And they may ask, well, but, hey,
他们可能会问，嗯，但是，嘿，
wait a minute.
等一下。
The you if you eat swan, we should be fine,
如果你吃天鹅，我们应该没问题。
because the arrival rate is not greater than the service rate.
因为到达率不大于服务率。
But if you is one, the queen is infinite.
但如果你是一个，那么女王就是无限的。
Why is that?
为什么这样做？
We'll talk more next lecture,
我们下一堂课会再详细讨论。
and you don't need,
而且你不需要，
we are not going to be asked this during the exam.
在考试中我们不会被问到这个问题。
But if the system is very bursting,
但如果系统非常繁忙，
there can be gaps.
可能会有间隙。
And during these gaps,
在这些间隙期间，
there is nothing in system.
系统中没有任何内容。
You lose that time, you lost,
你浪费了那个时间，你输了。
you never comes back because of births,
你再也没有回来，因为有了新生儿。
you are going to get in the future,
你将来会得到的。
are going to,
你们打算去吗？
then if you eliminate that gap,
那么如果你消除了那个间隙，
the number of arrival you are going to get in the future is going to be
你将来将会收到的到达数量将会是
greater than the server capacity,
超过服务器容量
because it's kind of these gaps where the system doesn't do anything.
因为这些间隙是系统不执行任何操作的时候。
When you have a very bursting arrival.
当你有一个非常繁忙的到达时。
This is a wasted time.
这是浪费时间。
It's a wasted capacity.
这是一种浪费的能力。
So that capacity cannot get back.
这样就无法恢复容量了。
That's why you can you fall behind in terms of capacity,
这就是为什么你在容量方面会落后的原因。
and you remain always behind.
而你始终保持在后面。
I I'm trying to give you an intuition,
我正在尝试给你一个直观的理解。
so it's like,
所以就像是，
it's not easy to get the intuition,
理解起来并不容易，
but this is good.
但这很好。
Okay.
好的。
What else I wanted to say here,
我还想在这里说的是，
by the way, you notice that for the general service time distribution,
顺便提一下，你注意到一般服务时间分布的情况。
the formula for the queuing delay,
排队延迟的公式是：
if exponential, you remember for exponential distribution,
如果是指指数分布，你应该记得指数分布的特征。
what was c one.
C One 是指 C 语言的第一个版本。C 语言是一种通用的高级编程语言，由贝尔实验室的丹尼斯·里奇在 1972 年至 1973 年间开发。C 语言在计算机科学和软件开发领域广泛应用，被认为是现代编程语言的基础。
If c is one,
如果c是1，
the equation,
方程式，
the queuing time for the general service distribution,
一般服务分布的排队时间
is going to reduce to the formula which you should expect
将会简化为你所期望的公式
for the exponential distribution.
指数分布
Let's take now our simple examples,
现在让我们来看一下我们的简单示例，
and then we are going to conclude the lecturers.
然后我们将总结讲座内容。
Let's say the user request.
假设用户发出了请求。
You have ten requests of you want to want a kilobytes disk,
您有十个请求，您希望获得一个千字节的磁盘。
write that request of each or 48 kilobytes data,
请求每次或48千字节的数据。
and the request.
和请求。
And the service are exponentially distributed.
而且服务时间是指数分布的。
Average service says 20 millisecond.
平均服务时间为20毫秒。
This is controller six time rotation latency and transfer time.
这是控制器的六次旋转延迟和传输时间。
And how utilize is a risk?
风险的利用程度如何？
Utilization is a formula, remember,
利用率是一个公式，记住。
is lambda times the service time.
是指每个任务的服务时间乘以λ。
Besides a formula average time to spending the qdq average the number
除了计算平均等待时间的公式之外，还有一种方法是计算平均等待时间的平均数。
of requesting the q now,
现在请求队列的操作。
this is a cure,
这是一种治疗方法，
not be noted here.
不在此处记录。
What is the average response time for this request?
这个请求的平均响应时间是多少？
This is the average response time.
这是平均响应时间。
It's very simple that the sum between the time is spending
时间之间的总和是很简单的。
the queue and time to service the request.
队列和处理请求的时间。
Let's do the computation.
让我们进行计算。
Lambda.
Lambda（拉姆达）是一种匿名函数的概念，它可以在编程语言中使用。Lambda函数通常用于简化代码，特别是在需要传递函数作为参数的情况下。Lambda函数可以在定义时直接使用，而不需要为其命名。在许多编程语言中，Lambda函数可以用于函数式编程和高阶函数的实现。
It's you have ten requests of a kilobytes,
您有十个请求，每个请求大小为一千字节。
this per second.
每秒钟。
So lambda,
所以lambda，
you have a very driving number of customers or request is ten per second.
你有非常高的客户数量或者请求量，每秒达到十个。
Ever, it's time to service the customers or a request 10 millisecond.
Ever，现在是时候为客户提供服务或处理一个请求了，每个请求需要10毫秒。
It was given here.
这里已经给出了。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
this is one that I have a very selfish time.
这是一个我非常自私的时刻。
Server utilization is lambda times the service time,
服务器利用率是 λ 倍的服务时间。
is 0.2 queuing time.
0.2是排队时间。
Now you are going to apply because everything is exponentially distributed.
现在你要进行应用，因为一切都是指数分布的。
Then you use a formula which is
然后你使用一个公式，该公式是
ATS service standard service time utilization over one minor stabilization.
ATS服务标准服务时间利用率在一次较小的稳定期间内。
And you get 5 million seconds.
你将获得500万秒。
Average length of the q is lambda times TQ is 0.05 seconds.
队列的平均长度 q 是 λ 倍的 TQ，即 0.05 秒。
Average time, the customer spending,
平均时间，顾客消费时间。
the sister sister system is a queuing time plus a service time.
姐妹系统是排队时间加上服务时间。
So it's through 20 million seconds plus5 million seconds.
所以是通过2000万秒加上500万秒。
Here is 25 million seconds.
这是2500万秒。
There are a lot of materials.
有很多材料。
Here you have some pointers.
这里有一些指针。
If you are interested more in the queuing theory,
如果你对排队理论更感兴趣的话，
is great.
很棒。
This is a fair game.
这是一场公平的游戏。
This is a mistake.
这是一个错误。
You are going to get this in meter two, not three.
你将会得到两米的长度，而不是三米。
Sorry, for the Tai Po.
对不起，关于大埔的问题。
This lecture is included for me to do.
这个讲座是为了我来做的。
And with that,
就这样，
I am done.
我完成了。
So in summary and remember about,
总结一下并记住以下内容：
we look at this,
我们来看一下这个。
how we are going to model the systems.
我们将如何对系统进行建模。
And these systems are modeled are they have a cure?
这些系统被建模的目的是为了找到解决方案吗？
He said, you spend some time in the cure plus have a speaks overhead,
他说，你需要花一些时间进行治疗，并且还有额外的演讲开销。
like rotational latency and so forth,
如旋转延迟等等，
and you have a transfer.
你有一次转账。
Then this will impact the effective bandwidth.
那么这将影响有效带宽。
Effective bandwidth is not like the device bandwidth,
有效带宽与设备带宽不同，
because of this fix overhead.
由于这个修复的开销。
And with then we learn a little bit about this skewing theory.
然后我们会稍微了解一下这个偏斜理论。
And in particular,
特别是，
I gave you the day as a the formulas for the queuing delay,
我给你提供了排队延迟的公式。
for mm one cures,
对于毫米来说，有一种治疗方法。
everything is exponentially distributed into arrival time.
所有事物的到达时间都服从指数分布。
And the service time and MG one q arrival times are still,
服务时间和MG一个队列的到达时间仍然是不变的。
inter arrival times are still exponentially distributed,
到达时间仍然服从指数分布，
but the but the service time has a general distribution.
但是服务时间具有一般分布。
And remember,
记住，
this is a formula for the queuing time,
这是一个计算排队时间的公式。
for the general distribution of the service time.
对于服务时间的一般分布。
And remember that in both cases was 71 and MD one q John cues is asking
请记住，在这两种情况下，71和MD都是John提出的问题。
for the when the utilization approaches one,
当利用率接近1时，
then the latency goes to infinity, the queuing delay, and therefore,
然后延迟变为无穷大，排队延迟也因此变大。
the response time goes to infinity.
响应时间趋向无穷大。
I'm stopping here.
我到这里停下来。
Good luck to at the midterm and really good luck for the next week.
祝你期中考试好运，下周也祝你好运。
If you have any questions,
如果你有任何问题，
please don't hesitate to ask on piazza.
请不要犹豫在 Piazza 上提问。
And i'll see you next week.
我下周会见到你。